Guide to the Mark Mothersbaugh Scores for "Music for Six-Sided Keyboard" MSS.517
Fales Library and Special Collections
Mark Mothersbaugh Scores for "Music for Six-Sided Keyboard"
2017
Fales Library and Special Collections
Mothersbaugh, Mark
MSS.517
1 linear foot in 4 oversize flat boxes
Mark Mothersbaugh is a singer, composer, record producer, author, and visual artist. Mothersbaugh co-founded the band Devo in 1973 with Gerald Casale and Bob Lewis, based on a satirical concept of the "de-evolution" and regression of humanity. The band's music, stage presence, and music videos combined pop sensibilities and synth instrumentation with social commentary, surrealist humor, and science fiction themes. Mothersbaugh has also composed numerous musical scores for film, television, commercials, and video games, in particular children's television shows and collaborations with director Wes Anderson. In addition to his musical career, Mothersbaugh is also a visual artist, with the notable touring retrospective in 2014, "Mark Mothersbaugh: Myopia." This collection consists of scores used in a live performance of Mothersbaugh's "Music for Six-Sided Keyboard," which took place at the NYU Skirball Center on May 4, 2017, as part of the Grey Art Gallery's programming for the "Myopia" exhibition.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of scores used in a live performance of Mark Mothersbaugh's "Music for Six-Sided Keyboard," which took place at the NYU Skirball Center on May 4, 2017, as part of the Grey Art Gallery's programming for the exhibition "Mark Mothersbaugh: Myopia."
Biographical Note
Mark Mothersbaugh (1950- ) is a singer, composer, record producer, author, and visual artist. He was born in Akron, Ohio and attended Kent State University to study art. Mothersbaugh co-founded the band Devo in 1973 with Gerald Casale and Bob Lewis, based on a satirical concept of the "de-evolution" and regression of humanity. The band's music, stage presence, and music videos combined pop sensibilities and synth instrumentation with social commentary, surrealist humor, and science fiction themes. Mothersbaugh has also composed numerous musical scores for film, television, commercials, and video games, in particular children's television shows and collaborations with director Wes Anderson. In addition to his musical career, Mothersbaugh is also a visual artist, with the notable touring retrospective in 2014, "Mark Mothersbaugh: Myopia." The exhibition was accompanied by a publication of the same name published by Princeton Architectural Press.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the Grey Art Gallery in August 2017; the accession number associated with this gift is 2017.187.
Custodial History
The scores that comprise this collection were printed for use in the live performance on May 4, 2017 at the NYU Skirball Center as part of the Grey Art Gallery's programming for the exhibition "Mark Mothersbaugh: Myopia." After the performance, Mothersbaugh gathered the scores together and gifted them to the Grey Gallery, who later transferred them to the Fales Library in August 2017. They arrived to Fales on August 8th, 2017. At the end of the live performance, Mothersbaugh threw a portion of the scores into the audience and gave signed pages from the scores to each of the performers, which may explain why the collection does not contain scores for each piece of the performance.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged by movement number or title.
Scores.; New wave musicians; Composers -- United States; Rock musicians.; Composition (Music) -- 21st century.; Mixed media (Music)
- "Attack on Ping Island" (#1), 2017; cuid25936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "Things We Need to Do Today" (#2), 2017; cuid25937 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
- "Denver Traffic Rush Hour Detour" (#3), 2017; cuid25938 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
- "Well-Intentioned Misinformation from the Heart" (#4), 2017; cuid25939 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
- "Where Does Food Come From?" (#5), 2017; cuid25940 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
- "Newscaster Trying to Get Her Story Straight" (#6), 2017; cuid25941 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
- "Cowboys Battling Drones" (#7), 2017; cuid25942 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- "Weaving Cozies for Real Men of Action" (#8), 2017; cuid25943 (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
- "The Last Time We Interlocked Playstation Controllers" (#9), 2017; cuid25944 (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
- "I Dreamt My Feet Were the Size of Boats" (#10), 2017; cuid25945 (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
- "The First Time We Drove to Cincinnati We Picked Up the Very First 1000 Vinyl Devo 45s, and it Was Magical" (#14), 2017; cuid25946 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
- "Camp Manitoc Was Both Wonderful and Horrifying" (#15), 2017; cuid25947 (Box 2, Folder 3-5)
- "Neunkirchen, 1977" (#16), 2017; cuid25948 (Box 2, Folder 6-9)
- "Optimistically Paranoid, But Hopeful" (#17), 2017; cuid25949 (Box 2, Folder 10-12)
- "Wishing I Knew Then What I Know Now" (#18), 2017; cuid25950 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
- "What's Round on the Ends and High in the Middle-Austin" (#19), 2017; cuid25951 (Box 3, Folder 4-7)
- "Texas May Be on the Bottom, But It's Still Tops!" (#20), 2017; cuid25952 (Box 3, Folder 8-11)
- #22, 2017; cuid25953 (Box 3, Folder 12, Box 4, Folder 1-3)
- "Akron! I Know Ye Well!" (#23), 2017; cuid25954 (Box 4, Folder 4-6)
- "Rubber Baby Mask" (#24), 2017; cuid25955 (Box 4, Folder 7-9)
- "6SK Funnel Rocket", 2017; cuid25956 (Box 4, Folder 10-12)
- "6SK Gut Rocket", 2017; cuid25957 (Box 4, Folder 13-15)